Lumos Maxima.
루모스 맥시마!
Harry. Harry.
해리, 해리!
Harry, open the door.
문 열어드려!
Marge. How lovely to see--
아가씨, 어서 와요
Uncle Vernon, I need you to sign this form.
이모부, 서명 좀 해주세요
What is it?
뭔데?
Nothing. School stuff.
학교에 낼 거예요
Later perhaps, if you behave.
착하게 굴면 해주마
I will if she does.
아줌마 하는 거 봐서요
-Oh, you're still here, are you? -Yes.
- 너, 아직 여기 사냐? - 그래요
Don't say yes in that ungrateful way.
'그래요'? 건방진 자식!
Damn good of my brother to keep you.
오빠는 마음도 좋지
He'd have been straight to an orphanage if he'd been dumped on my doorstep.
나 같으면 고아원에 쳐넣었어!
Is that my Dudders? Is that my little neffy-pooh?
이게 누구야? 귀여운 두들리!
Give us a kiss. Come on. Up, up.
예쁜 내 새끼
Take Marge's suitcase upstairs.
2층에 가방 올려놔!
Okay.
네
Finish that off for Mommy. Good boy, Rippy-pooh.
다 먹으렴, 내 귀염둥이
-Can I tempt you, Marge? -Just a small one.
- 한잔 할래? - 조금만 줘요
Excellent nosh, Petunia.
잘 먹었수, 언니
A bit more.
조금만 더요
Usually just a fry-up for me, what with 1 2 dogs.
평소엔 개들 땜에 대충 때워요
Just a bit more. That's a boy.
조금만 더요
You wanna try a little drop of brandy?
울애기도 줄까?
A little drop of brandy-brandy windy-wandy for Rippy-pippy-pooh?
우리 예쁜이 브랜디 마셔볼래?
What are you smirking at?
뭘 히죽대?
Where did you send the boy, Vernon?
쟤, 어디 다닌댔수?
St. Brutus'. It's a fine institution for hopeless cases.
구제불능 애들 다니는 학교 있어
Do they use a cane at St. Brutus', boy?
그 학교, 때리냐?
Oh, yeah.
네
Yeah. I've been beaten loads of times.
무진장 얻어터져요
Excellent. I won't have this namby-pamby...
다행이군
...wishy-washy nonsense about not beating people who deserve it.
그저 못된 놈들은 맞아야지
You mustn't blame yourself about how this one turned out.
쟤가 저꼴 된 거 오빠 탓 아냐
It's all to do with blood. Bad blood will out.
쟨 원래 핏줄이 나빠
What is it the boy's father did, Petunia?
애비 직업은 뭐였죠?
Nothing. He didn't work. He was unemployed.
직업 없었어요 백수였죠
-And a drunk too, no doubt? -That's a lie.
- 주정뱅이였고? - 웃기지 마요!
-What did you say? -My dad wasn't a drunk.
- 뭐라구? - 그런 분 아니셨어요!
Don't worry. Don't fuss, Petunia. I have a very firm grip.
괜찮아요, 컵을 너무 꽉 잡았나 봐
I think it's time you went to bed.
넌 가서 자
Quiet, Vernon. You, clean it up.
놔둬요, 어서 치워!
Actually, it's nothing to do with the father.
실은 애비보단
It's all to do with the mother. You see it all the time with dogs.
에미 영향이 크지 개를 봐도 그래요
If something's wrong with the bitch, then something's wrong with the pup.
암컷이 문제 있으면 새끼도 문제 있거든
Shut up! Shut up!
닥쳐요, 닥쳐!
Right.
쟨
Let me tell you....
아무리 생각해도...
Vernon!
오빠!
Vernon! Vernon, do something!
어떻게 좀 해봐요!
Stop!
안 돼!
I've got you, Marge. I've got you.
됐어, 잡았어!
-Hold on, hold on. -Get off.
- 꽉 잡아요 - 좀 떨어져라
-Don't you dare! -Sorry.
- 놓지 마! - 미안!
Oh, Vernon.
버논!
Oh, God.
맙소사!
Marge!
마지!
Please!
제발!
Come back!
돌아와!
You bring her back! You bring her back now.
데려와! 내 동생 데려와!
-You put her right! -No. She deserved what she got.
- 도로 데려와! - 죄값을 받은 거예요!
-Keep away from me. -You can't do magic outside school.
- 비켜요! - 마법 쓰면 퇴학야
-Yeah? Try me. -They won't let you back now.
- 겁 안나요 - 그럼 넌 갈 데도 없어
You've nowhere to go.
갈 곳 없는 신세야
I don't care. Anywhere is better than here.
어디든 여기보단 낫겠죠
"Welcome to the Knight Bus...
'갈 곳 없는 마법사는'
...emergency transport for the stranded witch or wizard.
'이 구조버스를 타십시오'
My name is Stan Shunpike, and I will be your conductor for this evening."
'전 승객을 모실 션파이크 차장입니다'
What you doing down there?
거기서 뭐하냐?
-I fell over. -What you fell over for?
- 넘어졌어요 - 왜 넘어져?
-I didn't do it on purpose. -Well, come on, then.
- 그냥요 - 그럼 빨리 타
Let's not wait for the grass to grow.
이러다 날 새겠다
-What you looking at? -Nothing.
- 뭘 보냐? - 아녜요
Well, come on, then. In.
빨리 올라타
No, no, no. I'll get this. You get in.
짐은 내가 실을게
Come on.
더
Come on. Move on, move on.
더 들어가, 들어가!
-Take her away, Ern. -Yeah, take it away, Ernie.
- 어니, 출발이요! - 그래, 출발해!
It's going to be a bumpy ride.
쬐끔 흔들릴 거야!
-What did you say your name was? -I didn't.
- 네 이름이 뭐랬지? - 말한 적 없어요
-Whereabouts are you headed? -The Leaky Cauldron. That's in London.
- 어디로 갈 건데? - 런던의 리키 콜드런
You hear that? "The Leaky Cauldron. That's in London."
들었죠? 런던 리키 콜드런
The Leaky Cauldron. If you have pea soup...
그 집 완두콩 스프
...make sure you eat it before it eats you.
조심해야 돼
-But the Muggles. Can't they see us? -Muggles?
- 저 머글들, 우릴 못봐요? - 쟤들?
They don't see nothing, do they?
아무것도 못봐
No, but if you jab them with a fork, they feel.
포크로 찌르면 아픈 건 알지
Ernie, little old lady at 1 2 o'clock!
저 할망구 조심해!
Ten, nine, eight...
10, 9, 8...
...seven, six, five...
7, 6, 5...
...four, three, three and a half...
4, 3, 3과 1/2...
...two, one and three quarters.
2, 1과 3/4
Yes!
됐다!
Who is that?
누구죠?
That man.
그 남자요
Who is--?
몰라?
That is Sirius Black, that is.
시리우스 블랙이잖아
Don't tell me you've never been hearing of Sirius Black.
시리우스 블랙을 모른단 말야?
He's a murderer.
살인마야
Got himself locked up in Azkaban for it.
아즈카반에서 탈옥했지
-How did he escape? -Well, that's the question, isn't it?
- 어떻게요? - 그게 의문이야!
He's the first one that done it.
첫 탈옥수래!
He was a big supporter of...
게다가 시리우스는
...You-Know-Who.
'그'의 추종자였대
I reckon you've heard of him.
'그'의 얘긴 들어봤지?
Yeah.
네
Him I've heard of.
들어봤어요
Ernie, two double-deckers at 1 2 o'clock.
12시 방향에 버스 2대 온다!
They're getting closer, Ernie.
점점 가까워져!
Ernie, they're right on top of us!
부딪치겠어!
Mind your head.
머리들 조심해!
Hey, guys? Guys?
이봐!
Why the long faces?
왜들 쭈그러져 있어?
Yeah, yeah. Nearly there. Nearly there.
다 왔어, 다 왔어!
-The Leaky Cauldron. -Next stop, Knockturn Alley.
- 리키 콜드런예요 - 다음은 녹턴 앨리!
Mr. Potter, at last.
포터군, 드디어 왔군
-Take it away, Ern. -Yeah, take it away, Ernie!
- 출발해요! - 그래, 출발!
Room 1 1.
11호실
Hedwig.
헤드위그!
Right smart bird you got there, Mr. Potter.
그 녀석, 꽤 영리하더구나
He arrived here just five minutes before yourself.
방금 혼자서 찾아왔더라
As Minister for Magic, it is my duty to inform you, Mr. Potter...
마법부 장관으로서 알려줄 게 있다
...earlier this evening your uncle's sister was located...
네 이모부 동생이 셰필드 남쪽의
...a little south of Sheffield, circling a chimney stack.
굴뚝 위에서 발견됐어
The Accidental Magic Reversal Department was dispatched immediately.
마법 사고 복구반을 급파했다
She has been properly punctured and her memory modified.
몸의 바람을 빼고 기억을 지웠어
She will have no recollection of the incident whatsoever.
앞으로 그 일은 기억 못할 게다
So that's that...
그러니까 모든 게...
...and no harm done.
잘 해결된 거지
Pea soup?
완두콩 스프?
No, thank you.
됐어요
-Minister? -Yes?
- 장관님 - 응?
-I don't understand. -Understand?
- 이해가 안 가요 - 뭘?
I broke the law. Underage wizards can't use magic at home.
전 법을 어겼어요 집에선 마법 쓰면 안 되잖아요
Come now. The Ministry doesn't send people to Azkaban...
걱정마, 그런 일로
...for blowing up their aunts.
아즈카반엔 안 보내
On the other hand, running away like that, given the state of things...
하지만 하필 이럴 때 그렇게 도망치는 건
...was very, very irresponsible.
무책임한 짓이지
-"The state of things," sir? -We have a killer on the loose.
- '이럴 때'라뇨? - 살인범이 탈옥했어
Sirius Black, you mean?
시리우스 블랙요?
But what's he got to do with me?
그게 저랑 무슨 상관이죠?
Nothing, of course. You're safe. And that's what matters.
상관없지 네가 무사하니까!
And tomorrow you'll be on your way back to Hogwarts.
게다가 내일이면 학교로 돌아갈 거고...
These are your new schoolbooks. I took the liberty...
새 학기 교과서다
...of having them brought here. Now Tom will show you to your room.
내가 준비시켰어 그만 방으로 올라가
Hedwig.
헤드위그
Oh, by the way, Harry. Whilst you're here, it would be best if you didn't...
여기 있는 동안... 나다니지 않는 게
...wander.
좋을 게다
Right! You gonna move that bus or what?
그 버스 움직일 거야, 말 거야?
Housekeeping.
청소 왔습니다!
I'll come back later.
나중에 오죠
I'm warning you, Hermione.
경고하는데
Keep that beast away from Scabbers, or I'll turn it into a tea cozy.
그 괴물 안 치우면 목도리로 만든다!
It's a cat, Ronald. What do you expect?
쥐를 쫓는 건
-It's in his nature. -A cat? Is that what they told you?
- 고양이 본능이야! - 고양이?
-Looks like a pig with hair. -That's rich...
- 털달린 돼지 같다! - 네 쥐는
...coming from the owner of that smelly old shoe brush.
더러운 수세미 같애!
Crookshanks, just ignore the mean little boy.
저런 꼴통 말 신경 쓰지마
Harry.
해리!
-Egypt. What's it like? -Brilliant. Loads of old stuff...
- 이집트? 좋았니? - 유적이 죽이더라!
...Iike mummies, tombs, even Scabbers enjoyed himself.
스캐버스도 좋았대
-Egyptians used to worship cats. -Along with the dung beetle.
- 이집트는 고양일 숭배했어 - 그래, 잘났다
-Not flashing that clipping again? -I haven't shown anyone.
- 또 여행 자랑야? - 내가 언제?
No, not a soul. Not unless you count Tom.
톰한테도 자랑했잖아
-The day maid. -Night maid.
- 청소부와 - 경비...
-Cook. -The bloke who fixed the toilet.
- 요리사... - 배관공...
-Harry. -Mrs. Weasley.
- 안녕 해리 - 위즐리 부인
-Good to see you, dear. -Good to see you.
- 얼굴 보니 좋구나 - 반가워요
-Got everything? -Yes.
- 준비물 챙겼니? - 네
-Yes? All your books? -It's all upstairs.
- 책 챙겼어? - 윗층에 있어요
-Your clothes? -Everything.
- 옷도? - 네
-Good boy. -Thank you.
- 잘했다 - 고마워요
-Harry Potter. -Mr. Weasley.
- 해리 포터 - 위즐리 씨
-Harry, wonder if I might have a word? -Yeah, sure.
- 얘기 좀 할까? - 네
-Hermione. -Good morning, Mr. Weasley.
- 헤르미온느 - 안녕하세요?
-Looking forward to a new term? -Yeah. It should be great.
- 학교 가니 좋니? - 네, 기대되요
Harry, some within the Ministry would strongly discourage me...
이런 얘기를 네게 하는 걸
...from divulging what I'm about to reveal to you.
마법부에선 반대한다만
But I think that you need to know the facts.
너도 알 건 알아야지
You are in danger.
넌 위험에 처해있어
Grave danger.
아주 큰 위험에...
Has this anything to do with Sirius Black, sir?
시리우스 블랙과 관계 있나요?
What do you know about Sirius Black, Harry?
그에 대해 뭘 아니?
-Only that he's escaped from Azkaban. -Do you know why?
- 탈옥했다는 거요 - 이유도 알아?
Thirteen years ago, when you stopped....
13년 전에 네가 '그'를...
-Voldemort. -Don't say his name.
- 볼드모트요? - 이름 말하지마
Sorry.
죄송해요
When you stopped You-Know-Who...
네가 '그'를 물리친 후
...Black lost everything.
시리우스도 끝장났지
But to this day, he still remains a faithful servant.
허나 놈은 아직도 '그'를 추종해
And in his mind...
시리우스는
...you are the only thing that stands in the way...
'그'에게 힘을 되찾아주려면
...of You-Know-Who returning to power.
널 없애야 한다고 믿고 있어
And that is why...
그래서
...he has escaped from Azkaban.
아즈카반을 탈출한 거지
To find you.
널 찾아내서...
And kill me.
죽이려구요?
Harry, swear to me that whatever you might hear...
약속해다오, 절대 놈을
...you won't go looking for Black.
찾아나서지 않겠다고...
Mr. Weasley...
위즐리 씨...
...why would I go looking for someone who wants to kill me?
절 노리는 자를 왜 찾아요?
Quick. Quick.
빨리, 빨리
Ron, Ron!
론!
Oh, for goodness' sake!
제발
Don't lose him!
스캐버스 간수 좀 잘해
I didn't mean to blow her up. I just--
너무 화 나서
-I lost control. -Brilliant.
- 자제가 안 되더라 - 잘했어!
Honestly, Ron, it's not funny. Harry was lucky not to be expelled.
뭘 잘해? 그건 퇴학감야!
I was lucky not to be arrested.
감옥갈 줄 알았어
I still think it was brilliant.
그래도 잘했어
Come on. Everywhere else is full.
이리 와 자리 있다
Who do you think that is?
저 사람 누구지?
-Professor R.J. Lupin. -Do you know everything?
- R.J. 루핀 교수 - 어떻게 알아?
How is it she knows everything?
얜 모르는 게 없어!
-It's on his suitcase, Ronald. -Oh.
- 가방에 써 있잖아 - 아
-Do you think he's really asleep? -Seems to be. Why?
- 이 분, 자는 거지? - 그런 것 같애, 왜?
I gotta tell you something.
할 말이 있어
Let me get this straight. Sirius Black escaped from Azkaban...
시리우스가 널 찾으러
-...to come after you? -Yeah.
- 탈옥했다구? 응 -
But they'll catch Black, won't they?
곧 잡힐 거야
-I mean, everyone's looking for him. -Sure.
- 다들 찾고 있잖아 - 그럴까?
Except no one's ever broken out of Azkaban before...
그자는 아즈카반도 탈출했어
-...and he's a murderous, raving lunatic. -Thanks, Ron.
- 미친 살인마라구 - 고맙구나
Why are we stopping?
왜 멈추지?
We can't be there yet.
아직 멀었는데...
What's going on?
무슨 일이지?
I don't know. Maybe we've broken down.
기차가 고장났나 봐
Ouch, Ron. That was my foot.
내 발 밟았어!
There's something moving out there.
밖에 뭐가 움직여
I think someone's coming aboard.
누가 기차에 타는 것 같애!
Bloody hell! What's happening?
엄마야! 무슨 일이야?
Harry.
해리?
Harry, are you all right?
괜찮니?
Thank you.
고마워
Here, eat this. It'll help.
먹어봐, 진정될 거야
It's all right. It's chocolate.
초콜릿이야
What was that thing that came?
아까 그거, 뭐죠?
It was a dementor. One of the guards of Azkaban. It's gone now.
아즈카반의 간수 디멘터야
It was searching the train for Sirius Black.
시리우스를 찾으러 왔나 봐
If you'll excuse me, I need to have a little word with the driver.
난 기관사 좀 만나고 오마
Eat. You'll feel better.
먹어, 좀 나아질 거야
What happened to me?
어떻게 된 거야?
Well, you sort of went rigid.
네 몸이 굳었었어
We thought maybe you were having a fit or something.
경련하듯...
And did either of you two...
너희도
...you know...
나처럼...
-...pass out? -No.
- 기절했었니? - 아니
I felt weird, though.
하지만 무서웠어
Like I'd never be cheerful again.
그 기분, 못 잊을 거야
But someone was screaming.
누가 비명을 질렀었어
A woman.
여자였는데...
No one was screaming, Harry.
비명 지른 사람 없어
Welcome! Welcome to another year at Hogwarts.
다시 만나게 돼 반갑습니다
Now, I'd like to say a few words...
연회 시작 전에
...before we all become too befuddled by our excellent feast.
전달할 사항이 몇가지 있습니다
First, I'm pleased to welcome Professor R.J. Lupin...
루핀 교수부터 소개하죠
...who's kindly consented to fill the post...
'어둠의 마법 방어술'을
...of Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher.
새 학기부터 맡으실 겁니다
Good luck, professor.
잘 부탁합니다!
Of course. That's why he knew to give you the chocolate, Harry.
그래서 초콜릿을 줬군 해리!
Potter. Is it true you fainted?
기절했었다며?
-I mean, you actually fainted? -Shove off, Malfoy.
- 진짜 뻗었었냐? - 닥쳐, 말포이!
-How did he find out? -Just forget it.
- 어떻게 알았지? - 신경 꺼
Our Care of Magical Creatures teacher...
전임 교수께서
...has decided to retire...
다리를 물어뜯긴 후
...in order to spend more time with his remaining limbs.
사퇴하신
Fortunately, I'm delighted to announce...
'신비한 동물 돌보기' 과목도
...that his place will be taken by none other...
후임자가 결정됐습니다
...than our own Rubeus Hagrid.
루베우스 해그리드입니다!
Finally, on a more disquieting note...
이 건은 좀 심각한 건데...
...at the request of the Ministry of Magic...
마법부의 요청으로
...Hogwarts will, until further notice, play host to the dementors of Azkaban...
당분간 디멘터들이 여기 머물 겁니다
...until such a time as Sirius Black is captured.
시리우스 블랙이 체포될 때까지...
The dementors will be stationed at every entrance to the grounds.
그들은 각 출입구에 배치될 겁니다
Now whilst I've been assured...
수업 방해 안 한다는
...that their presence will not disrupt our day-to-day activities...
약속은 받았지만
...a word of caution.
조심하세요
Dementors are vicious creatures. They'll not distinguish...
그들은 사악합니다
...between the one they hunt and the one who gets in their way.
누구든 방해가 되면 사정없이 공격하죠
Therefore, I must warn each and every one of you...
당부컨대, 절대 그들에게
...to give them no reason to harm you.
공격할 구실을 주지 마세요
It is not in the nature of a dementor to be forgiving.
디멘터에게 자비란 없습니다
But you know, happiness can be found...
하지만, 암울한 때에도
...even in the darkest of times...
즐거움은 있는 법
...if one only remembers to turn on the light.
마음의 불빛을 밝힙시다!
Fortuna Major.
포르투나 소령
Here, listen. She just won't let me in.
또 안 들여보내줘
-Fortuna Major. -No, no. Wait, wait.
- 포르투나 소령 - 잠깐만
Watch this.
좀 들어봐
-Amazing. Just with my voice. -Fortuna Major.
- 대단하지, 내 목청? - 포르투나 소령
-Yes, all right. Go in. -Thank you.
- 알았어, 들어가 - 고마워요
Still doing that after three years.
저 버릇 여전하네
-She can't even sing. -Exactly.
- 음치 주제에... - 못 말려
-Hey, man.
안녕
-Oh, God. -That's awful.
- 어휴 - 기분 나쁘겠다
Green. That's a monkey.
원숭이 같은데?
-What is that? -You call that a monkey?
- 그게 뭐야? - 그게 원숭이냐?
Do not give him one again.
사탕 주지 마
Hey, Neville, try an elephant.
네빌, 코끼리 해 봐
-Ron, catch. -I will.
- 론, 받아 - 그래
I think we have a winner.
제일 낫다
-Oh, don't try one of them. -Oh, no.
- 그건 하지 마! - 저런
Look at him. His face.
쟤 얼굴 좀 봐!
Welcome, my children.
모두들 반가워요
In this room, you shall explore the noble art of Divination.
여러분은 이제 점술을 배울 겁니다
In this room, you shall discover if you possess the Sight.
앞을 보는 '눈'을 키우는 거죠
Hello. I am Professor Trelawney.
난 트릴로니 교수예요
Together we shall cast ourselves into the future.
함께 미래를 탐구해 봅시다!
This term, we'll focus on Tasseomancy, the art of reading tea leaves.
새 학기에 배울 건 찻잎 해독법이에요
So please, take the cup of the person sitting opposite you.
찻잔을 맞바꿔 들어봐요
What do you see?
뭐가 보이죠?
The truth lies buried like a sentence deep within a book, waiting to be read.
숨은 보물 캐듯 진리를 캐내려면
But first, you must broaden your minds.
마음을 열어야 돼요
-First, you must look beyond. -What a load of rubbish.
- 멀리 내다 봐요! - 헛소리 뿐이군
-Where did you come from? -Me?
- 너, 언제 왔어? - 나?
-I've been here all this time. -You, boy....
- 쭉 여깄었어 - 너!
Is your grandmother quite well?
할머니 잘 계시니?
I think so.
그럴걸요?
I wouldn't be so sure of that. Give me the cup.
과연 그럴까? 컵 줘봐
Pity.
안됐다
Broaden your minds.
마음을 열어요!
Your aura is pulsing, dear. Are you in the beyond?
네겐 죽음이 보여 저승문턱에 있어!
-I think you are. -Sure.
- 확실해 - 그래요?
Look at the cup. Tell me what you see.
친구 껄 읽어봐
Yeah.
네
Harry's got sort of a wonky cross. That's trials and suffering.
고난을 뜻하는 찌그러진 십자가와
And that there could be the sun and that's happiness.
행복을 뜻하는 태양이 있네요
So...
그러니까...
...you're gonna suffer, but you're gonna be happy about it.
넌 고난을 통해 행복해질 거야
Give me the cup.
줘봐
Oh, my dear boy.
이럴 수가...
My dear...
이건...
...you have the Grim.
'죽음의 개'란다
The Grin? What's the Grin?
'죽음의 재'가 뭐죠?
Not the Grin, you idiot. The Grim.
'재'가 아니고 '개'야
"Taking form of a giant spectral dog.
'유령처럼 생긴 개로'
It's among the darkest omens in our world.
'큰 재앙을 예고하는'
It's an omen...
'죽음의'
...of death."
'징조이다'
You don't think that Grim thing's got anything to do with Sirius Black?
개가 시리우스와 연관 있을까?
Oh, honestly, Ron. If you ask me, Divination's a woolly discipline.
점술은 너무 애매모호한 학문야
Now, Ancient Runes, that's a fascinating subject.
고대 문자가 진짜 학문이지
Ancient Runes? Exactly how many classes are you taking?
고대 문자? 너 몇 과목 듣냐?
A fair few.
몇 과목 안 돼
Hang on. That's not possible.
고대문자랑 점술은
Ancient Runes is in the same time as Divination.
수업시간이 같잖아!
You have to be in two classes at once.
한꺼번에 두 개 듣냐?
Don't be silly. How could anyone be in two classes at once?
어떻게 두 개를 같이 들어?
" Broaden your minds. Use your lnner Eye to see the future."
'멀리 보세요 마음의 문을 여세요'
That's it. Come on, now. Come closer. Less talking, if you don't mind.
가까이 모여봐 조용히들 해
I got a real treat for you today.
오늘 수업은 재밌을 거야
A great lesson. So follow me.
따라와
Right, you lot. Less chattering. Form a group over there.
조용히 하고 모여봐
And open your books to page 49.
49페이지 펴
Exactly how do we do that?
이걸 어떻게 펴요?
Just stroke the spine, of course. Goodness me.
쓰다듬어 줘! 그것도 몰라?
-Don't be such a wimp, Longbottom. -I'm okay. Okay.
- 겁 많긴, 쪼다... - 나 괜찮아
-I think they're funny. -Oh, yeah. Terribly funny.
- 이 책, 재밌는데? - 재미 좋아하네
Witty. God, this place has gone to the dogs.
저런 멍청이도 교수라고!
Wait until Father hears Dumbledore's got this oaf teaching classes.
우리 아빠가 알면 기절할 거야
Shut up, Malfoy.
그만해, 말포이
Dementor! Dementor!
디멘터다!
-Just ignore him. -You're supposed to stroke it.
- 무시해 - 책 등을 쓰다듬어 줘
Yeah.
응
Isn't he beautiful?
정말 예쁜 녀석이지?
Say hello to Buckbeak.
벅빅이야, 인사해
Hagrid, exactly what is that?
해그리드, 그게 뭐예요?
That, Ron, is a hippogriff.
히포그리프란다
First thing you wanna know is they're very proud creatures.
자존심이 꽤 강한 짐승이지
Very easily offended. You do not want to insult a hippogriff.
쉽게 맘 상하니까 화나게 하지 마
It may be the last thing you ever do.
그랬다간 큰일 생겨
Now, who'd like to come and say hello?
누가 인사해 볼래?
Well done, Harry. Well done.
좋았어, 해리
Come on now.
나와봐
Now...
먼저
...you have to let him make the first move. It's only polite. So...
움직일 때까지 기다려
...step up. Give him a nice bow.
다가서서 인사한 뒤
Then you wait and see if he bows back.
녀석도 인사하면 만져도 돼
If he does, you can go and touch him.
녀석이 인사 안 하면...
If not-- Well, we'll get to that later.
그 얘긴 이따 하자
Just make your bow.
인사해
Nice and low.
공손하게...
Back off, Harry. Back off.
물러서, 해리!
Keep still.
꼼짝마
Well done, Harry. Well done. Here, you big brute, you.
잘했어, 아주 좋아 귀여운 녀석
Right. I think you can go and pat him now.
이젠 쓰다듬어줘도 돼
Go on. Don't be shy.
괜찮아, 겁먹지 마
Nice and slow, now. Nice and slow. Slow.
천천히, 천천히...
Not so fast, Harry.
서둘지 마
Slow down, Harry. That's it....
천천히...
Nice and slow. Now let him come to you.
이젠 다가오게 기다려
That's it....
그렇지...
Yes!
좋아!
Well done! Well done, Harry, well done!
잘했어! 잘했어, 해리!
Does he get to fly?
타고 날 건가?
-I think he may let you ride him now. -What?
- 이젠 타도 될 거야 - 네?
-Come on. -Hey, hey, hey!
- 자 - 잠깐만요!
Put you over here, just behind the wing joint.
타 봐 날갯죽지 뒤가 안전해
Don't pull out any of his feathers, because he won't thank you for that.
깃털은 뽑지 마 안 좋아할 거야
Well done, Harry, and well done, Buckbeak.
잘했다, 해리 잘했어, 벅빅
That was wicked, Harry!
진짜 멋졌어, 해리!
Oh, please.
놀고들 있네
Well done, well done.
잘했어
-How am I doing me first day? -Brilliant, professor.
- 내 첫수업 어때? - 훌륭해요, 교수님
You're not dangerous at all, are you, you great ugly brute!
난 니깐 거 겁 안나 이 못난 괴물아!
Malfoy, no....
말포이!
No!
안 돼!
Buckbeak!
벅빅! 벅빅!
Whoa, whoa, whoa....
워, 워...
Whoa! Buckbeak!
워, 벅빅!
Away, you silly creature....
이 멍청한 녀석!
-It's killed me! -Calm down. It's just a scratch!
- 죽을 것 같애! - 좀 긁힌 것뿐이야
Hagrid!
해그리드
-He has to be taken to the hospital. -I'm the teacher. I'll do it.
- 병원 데려가요! - 알았어, 데려간다
-You're gonna regret this. -Class dismissed!
- 가만 두나 봐라 - 수업 끝!
You and your bloody chicken!
둘 다 가만 안 둬
Does it hurt terribly, Draco?
많이 아파, 말포이?
It comes and it goes. Still, I consider myself lucky.
가끔 욱신대 폼프리 교수 말이
Madam Pomfrey said another minute and I could've lost my arm.
조금만 늦었어도 팔이 잘렸을 거래
-I can't do homework for weeks. -Listen to the idiot.
- 숙제도 못했어 - 쪼다같은 놈
-He's really laying it on thick, isn't he? -At least Hagrid didn't get fired.
- 엄살 되게 피네 - 해고는 안 됐잖아
I hear Draco's father's furious. We haven't heard the end of this.
해그리드? 아직 몰라, 쟤 아빠 화났대
-He's been sighted! -Who?
- 그가 목격됐대! - 누구?
Sirius Black!
시리우스!
Dufftown? That's not far from here.
더프타운? 이 근처잖아!
You don't think he'd come to Hogwarts, do you?
설마 여긴 오지 않겠지?
-With dementors at every entrance? -Dementors?
- 디멘터가 지키잖아 - 디멘터?
He slipped past them once. Who's to say he won't do it again?
아즈카반은 디멘터가 안 지켰냐?
That's right. Black could be anywhere. It's like trying to catch smoke.
맞아 어디든 안심 못해
Like trying to catch smoke with your bare hands.
그자를 잡는 건 맨손으로 뜬구름 잡기야
Intriguing, isn't it?
뭔지 궁금하지?
Would anyone like to venture a guess...
뭐가 들었는지
...as to what is inside?
맞춰 볼 사람?
-That's a boggart, that is. -Very good, Mr. Thomas.
- 보가트예요 - 아주 좋아, 토마스
Now, can anybody tell me what a boggart looks like?
보가트는 어떻게 생겼지?
-No one knows. -When did she get here?
- 알 수 없죠 - 쟨 언제 왔어?
Boggarts are shape-shifters.
계속 변신해요
They take the shape of whatever a person fears the most.
상대가 두려워하는 사물로...
-That's what makes them so-- -So terrifying, yes, yes, yes....
- 그래서 더욱... - 무서운 존재지
Luckily, a very simple charm exists to repel a boggart.
하지만 퇴치할 수 있는 주문이 있어
Let's practice it now. Without wands, please.
연습해보자 지팡인 꺼내지 마
After me. Riddikulus!
따라해 봐 리디큘러스!
-Riddikulus! -Very good.
- 리디큘러스! - 좋아
A little louder and very clear. Listen:
좀 더 크고 분명하게!
-Riddikulus!
- 리디큘러스!
-This class is ridiculous. -Very good.
- 웃기고 있네 - 잘했다
So much for the easy part. You see, the incantation alone is not enough.
여기까진 쉽지 헌데 주문만으론 부족해
What really finishes a boggart is laughter.
완벽한 퇴치법은 웃음 소리야
You need to force it to assume a shape you find truly amusing.
놈을 웃기는 걸로 변신시켜야 돼
Let me explain. Neville, would you join me, please?
설명해주지 네빌, 나와볼래?
Come on, don't be shy. Come on.
괜찮아, 나와봐
Come on.
얼른
Hello. Neville, what frightens you most of all?
안녕, 넌 뭐가 제일 두렵니?
Professor Snape.
스네이프 교수요
-Sorry? -Professor Snape.
- 뭐라구? - 스네이프 교수요
Professor Snape. Yes, frightens all.
다 겁내지
-You live with your grandmother. -I don't want it to turn into her, either.
- 너, 할머니랑 살지? - 울 할머니도 안 돼요
No...
걱정 마
...it won't. I want you to picture her clothes.
할머니 옷차림을
Only her clothes, very clearly, in your mind.
머리에 떠올려봐
-She carries a red handbag-- -We don't need to hear.
- 빨간 손가방에... - 말 안 해도 돼
As long as you see it, we'll see it. Now, when I open that wardrobe...
상상만 해 내가 옷장을 열면
...here's what I want you to do. Excuse me.
이렇게 해, 잠깐만...
Imagine Professor Snape in your grandmother's clothes.
할머니 옷 입은 스네이프를 상상해
Can you do that?
할 수 있지?
Yes. Wand at the ready.
지팡이 준비하고
One, two, three.
하나, 둘, 셋!
Think, Neville, think.
집중해, 집중!
Riddikulus!
리디큘러스!
Wonderful, Neville, wonderful! Incredible! Okay...
좋아, 네빌, 훌륭해!
...to the back, Neville. Everyone, form a line....
모두 뒤로 가서 줄 서!
I want everyone to picture the thing they fear the very most...
각자 두려운 걸 떠올린 뒤
...and turn it into something funny.
우스꽝스럽게 바꿔봐
Next! Ron!
다음! 론!
Concentrate. Face your fear. Be brave!
용기있게 맞서 겁내지 마!
Wand at the ready, Ron.
지팡이 내밀고...
Riddikulus!
리디큘러스!
Yes!
그렇지!
You see? Very good, very good!
봤지? 잘했어!
Marvelous! Absolutely, very, very enjoyable! Parvati! Next!
훌륭해! 재밌는 발상이야! 패르바티!
Show us what you see.
네 상상력 좀 보자
Keep your nerve. Steady.
주눅들 필요없어
Riddikulus!
리디큘러스!
And next! Step up, step up!
다음! 앞으로 나와!
Wonderful, wonderful!
좋아, 좋아!
Here!
안 돼!
Riddikulus!
리디큘러스!
Right. Sorry about that. That's enough for today.
미안! 오늘은 그만하자
Collect your books from the back.
교과서 챙기고...
That's the end of the lesson. Thank you! Sorry!
다음 시간에 보자
Sorry, you can have too much of a good thing.
좋은 공부도 지나치면 안 돼
Remember, these visits to Hogsmeade village are a privilege.
호그스미드 방문은 큰 특권입니다
Should your behavior reflect poorly on the school...
학교에 누가 되는 짓 하면
...that privilege shall not be extended again.
그런 특권, 다신 못 누려요
No permission form signed, no visiting the village.
보호자가 서명한 허가서 없인 못 가
That's the rule, Potter.
규칙이야, 해리
Those with permission, follow me. Those without, stay put.
서명받은 사람만 따라와
I thought if you signed it, then I could--
교수님 서명은 안 돼요?
I can't. Only a parent or a guardian can sign.
부모나 보호자만 돼
Since I am neither, it would be inappropriate.
난 둘 다 아니잖니
I'm sorry, Potter. That's my final word.
미안하다 어쩔 수가 없구나
Forget about it, guys. See you later.
난 안 되겠다, 다녀와
Professor, can I ask you something?
여쭤볼 게 있어요
You want to know why I stopped you facing that boggart, yes?
왜 네 보가트를 대신 막았냐구?
I thought it'd be obvious.
볼드모트가
I assumed it would take the shape of Lord Voldemort.
나타날 줄 알았거든
I did think of Voldemort at first.
처음엔 볼드모트가 생각났죠
But then I remembered that night on the train...
그 순간 기찻간 사건이
-...and the dementor. -I'm very impressed.
- 떠올랐어요 - 대단한데
That suggests what you fear the most is fear itself.
네가 두려워하는 건 두려움 자체군
This is very wise.
현명해
Before I fainted...
기절 직전
...I heard something.
뭔가 들렸어요
A woman...
한 여자의...
...screaming.
비명 소리...
Dementors force us to relive our very worst memories.
우리가 고통스런 기억을 떠올릴 때
Our pain becomes their power.
디멘터는 힘을 얻지
I think it was my mother...
엄마의 비명 같애요
...the night she was murdered.
살해되던 밤의...
The very first time I saw you, Harry, I recognized you immediately.
처음 본 순간 난 널 알아봤어
Not by your scar, by your eyes.
흉터가 아닌 눈빛으로...
They're your mother, Lily's.
네 엄마 릴리의 눈빛이었지
Yes.
그래
Oh, yes. I knew her.
난 네 엄마를 잘 알아
Your mother was there for me at a time when no one else was.
내가 힘들 때 날 도와줬지
Not only was she a singularly gifted witch...
뛰어난 마법사인데다
...she was also an uncommonly kind woman.
마음씨도 아주 고왔어
She had a way of seeing the beauty in others...
남의 장점을 알아봐줬지
...even, and most especially, when that person could not see it in themselves.
본인 자신이 그 장점을 모르고 있을 때 조차도...
And your father, James, on the other hand...
네 아버지 제임스는
...he....
말썽을
He had a certain, shall we say, talent for trouble.
일으키는 재주가 특별했지
A talent, rumor has it, he passed on to you.
소문으론 그 재능을... 네가 물려 받았다더군
You're more like them than you know, Harry.
넌 부모님을 닮았어
In time, you'll come to see just how much.
때가 오면 알게 될게다
Honeyduke's Sweetshop is brilliant, but nothing beats Zonko's Joke Shop.
종코 장난감 가게 끝내주더라
We never got to go to the Shrieking Shack.
'비명을 지르는 오두막집'엔
-You heard it's the most-- -Haunted building in Britain. I know.
- 못 가봤어 - 유령이 출몰한다는 집?
What's going on?
무슨 일이지?
Probably Neville forgot the password again.
네빌이 또 암호를 잊었나?
-Hey. -Oh, you're there.
- 내가 뭘? - 거깄었냐?
Let me through, please. Excuse me! I'm Head Boy!
비켜봐, 비켜봐 나 회장이야!
Get back, all of you.
다들 물러서
No one is to enter this dormitory until it's been searched.
조사 끝날 때까진 아무도 못 들어가
The Fat Lady! She's gone!
뚱보 여인이 사라졌어!
Serves her right. She was a terrible singer.
쌤통이다, 그 음치!
It's not funny, Ron.
농담이 나와?
Keep calm, everyone. Break into fours. Back to your common room.
다들 진정해 네 명씩 짝지어서 돌아가
-Be quiet. -Make way.
- 조용히 해 - 비켜
-The headmaster's here. -Come on, move.
- 교장 선생님 오셨어! - 비켜, 비켜!
You heard. Move!
비키랬잖아!
Mr. Filch? Round up the ghosts.
필치 씨, 유령들 소집해서
Tell them to search every painting in the castle to find the Fat Lady.
온 성을 뒤져 여인을 찾으시오
There's no need for ghosts, professor.
유령들 부를 거 없습니다
The Fat Lady's there.
뚱보 여인 저깄어요
Mind where you're going! Slow down!
어딜 올라가? 거기 서!
You listen! I'm Head Boy!
회장 말 안 들려?
-Come back here! -Keep moving!
- 이리 돌아와! - 좀 비켜봐!
Dear lady, who did this to you?
뚱보 여인, 누가 이랬소?
Eyes like the devil, he's got, and a soul as dark as his name.
두 눈은 악마를 닮았고 영혼은 그 이름처럼 어두운
It's him, headmaster. The one they all talk about.
그 자가 성 안에 와 있어요
He's here, somewhere in the castle!
여기 왔다구요
Sirius Black!
시리우스 블랙이!
Secure the castle, Mr. Filch. The rest of you, to the Great Hall.
성문을 잠궈요 모두 연회장으로 가!
I've searched the Astronomy Tower and the Owlery. There's nothing there.
천문탑과 부엉이장엔 아무것도 없습니다
-Thank you. -The third floor's clear too, sir.
- 수고했소 - 3층도 이상 없어요
-Very good. -I've done the dungeons.
- 다행이군 - 지하 감옥두요
No sign of Black, nor anywhere else in the castle.
흔적도 없습니다
I didn't really expect him to linger.
여태 여깄을리 없지
Remarkable feat, don't you think?
솜씨가 놀랍군요
To enter Hogwarts Castle on one's own...
혼자 호그와트에
-...completely undetected? -Quite remarkable, yes.
- 침입하다니... - 동감이요
Any theories on how he managed it?
가능한 방법이 있나요?
Many. Each as unlikely as the next.
많죠, 쉽진 않지만...
You may recall...
루핀 교수 임용에 대해
...prior to the start of term I expressed concerns...
제가 우려했던 거
...about your appointment of Professor--
기억하시죠?
Not a single professor inside this castle would help Sirius Black enter it.
시리우스를 도울 자는 이 성엔 없소
I'm quite convinced the castle is safe...
성은 안전한 듯하니
...and I'm more than willing to send the students to their houses.
기숙사 문을 내일 다시 엽시다
What about Potter? Should he be warned?
해리에겐 주의를 시켜야죠?
Perhaps. But for now, let him sleep.
지금은 자게 놔둬요
For in dreams, we enter a world that's entirely our own.
꿈꿀 땐 간섭받지 말아야지
Let them swim in the deepest ocean or glide over the highest cloud.
바닷속을 맘껏 헤엄치고 구름 위를 날게 놔둬요
Turn to page 394.
교과서 394쪽을 펴라
Excuse me, sir. Where's Professor Lupin?
교수님 루핀 교수님은요?
That's not really your concern, is it, Potter?
그건 네가 상관할 바 아냐
Suffice it to say your professor finds himself incapable of teaching...
'사정상 결근했다' 그렇게만 알아둬
...at the present time. Turn to page 394.
모두 394쪽 펴
"Werewolves"?
늑대 인간?
Sir, we just learned about red caps and hinkypunks.
힝키펑크를 배우던 참인데요
-We're not meant to start that for weeks. -Quiet.
- 진도가 틀려요 - 시끄러워
When did she come in? Did you see her come in?
쟤 언제 들어온 거야?
Now, which one of you can tell me the difference...
애니마구스와 늑대인간의
...between an Animagus and a werewolf?
차이를 아는 사람?
No one?
없나?
-How disappointing. -Please, sir.
- 실망스럽군 - 교수님
An Animagus is a wizard who elects to turn into an animal.
애니마구스는 마법사가 둔갑한 짐승이고
A werewolf has no choice.
늑대 인간은
With each full moon...
보름달 뜰 때마다
...he no longer remembers who he is. He'd kill his best friend.
기억을 잃고 변신하는 존재죠
The werewolf only responds to the call of its own kind.
동족 울음소리에만 반응해요
Thank you, Mr. Malfoy. That's the second time...
고맙다, 말포이
...you've spoken out of turn, Miss Granger.
나서는 건 여전하군
Are you incapable of restraining yourself...
자제력이 없는 건가
...or do you take pride in being an insufferable know-it-all?
잘난 척이 취미인가?
-He's got a point, you know. -Five points from Gryffindor.
- 정곡을 찔렀군 - 그리핀도르 5점 감점
As an antidote to your ignorance, and on my desk, by Monday morning...
월요일 아침까지 두루마리 두 개 분량의
...two rolls of parchment on the werewolf, with emphasis...
리포트를 내라, 주제는
-...on recognizing it. -It's Quidditch tomorrow.
- '늑대인간 구별법' - 내일 퀴디치 시합 있습니다
Then I suggest you take extra care, Mr. Potter.
그럼 시합할 때 몸 조심해
Loss of limb will not excuse you.
팔 부러져도 숙제는 해야 돼
Page 394.
394쪽을 봐
The term "werewolf"...
'늑대 인간'이란 말은
...is a contraction of the Anglo-Saxon word " wer"...
앵글로 색슨어 '워'에서 나온 말로
...which means "man," and "wolf." Werewolf, man-wolf.
'늑대가 된 인간'이란 뜻이다
There are several ways to become a werewolf.
늑대 인간이 되는
They include being given the power of shape-shifting...
원인은 여러가지다
...being bitten by a werewolf....
늑대 인간에게 물리거나...
Go, Harry! Go, Harry!
해리 파이팅!
Aresto momentum!
아레스토 모멘텀!
-He looks a bit peaky, doesn't he? -Peaky?
- 얼굴이 창백한데? - 창백?
What do you expect? He fell over 1 00 feet.
당연하지! 추락했는데!
Let's walk you off a tower and see what you look like.
너도 떨어뜨려봐? 꼴이 어떨까?
Probably a right sight better than he normally does.
지금 꼴보단 낫겠지
-How are you feeling? -Oh, brilliant.
- 기분 좀 어때? - 아주 좋아
You gave us a right good scare.
사람 놀래키긴!
-What happened? -Well, you fell off your broom.
- 어떻게 된 거야? - 네가 추락했어
Really? I meant the match. Who won?
시합 말이야, 졌니?
No one blames you, Harry.
디멘터 탓이야
Dementors aren't supposed to be on the grounds. Dumbledore's furious.
거긴 오면 안 되는데... 교장이 화나서
After he saved you, he sent them off.
즉시 내쫓았어
There's something else you should know too.
말해줄 게 또 있어
When you fell, your broom sort of blew into the Whomping Willow, and....
떨어질 때 빗자루가 '커다란 버드나무'에 부딪혀서...
Well....
이렇게 됐어
I'm sorry to hear about your broomstick.
빗자루 얘기 들었다
Is there no chance of fixing it?
고쳐서 쓸 순 없대?
No.
네
Professor, why do the dementors affect me so?
디멘터를 보면 왜 전 기절하죠?
-I mean, more than everyone else? -Listen.
- 딴 애들은 안 그러는데... - 들어보렴
Dementors are the foulest creatures to walk this earth.
디멘터는 가장 추악한 존재야
They feed on every good feeling, every happy memory...
상대의 행복한 기억을 빨아먹지
...until a person is left with absolutely nothing but his worst experiences.
가장 고통스런 기억만 남을 때까지...
You are not weak, Harry.
넌 나약한 게 아냐, 해리
Dementors affect you most because there are true horrors in your past.
남다른 공포를 겪어봤기 때문에
Horrors your classmates can scarcely imagine.
특별히 디멘터에 약한 거지
You have nothing to be ashamed of.
창피해할 거 없어
-I'm scared, professor. -I'd consider you a fool if you weren't.
- 두려워요 - 안 그러면 이상하지
I need to know how to fight them. You could teach me.
어떻게 물리치죠?
You made the one on the train go away.
기차에서 물리치셨잖아요
There was only one that night.
그땐 한 놈이었어
-But you made it go away. -I don't pretend to be an expert, Harry.
- 어쨌든요 - 비록 난 전문가는 아니지만
But as the dementors seem to have developed an interest in you...
디멘터가 네게 관심을 갖고 있으니
...perhaps I should teach you. But after the holidays.
휴가 끝난 뒤 퇴치법을 알려주마
For now, I need to rest.
지금은 좀 피곤해
Last call for Hogsmeade! Come on, now!
호그스미드로 출발한다! 서둘러!
-Guys, let me go. -Clever, Harry.
- 놔! - 잔머린!
-But not clever enough. -We've got a better way.
- 어딜 가려구? - 방법이 틀렸어
-I'm trying to get to Hogsmeade. -We know.
- 호그스미드에 가야 돼! - 알아
We'll get you there.
데려다 줄게
-We'll show you a quicker way. -lf you pipe down.
- 방법이 있지 - 조용히 해
-Bless him. -Let me go! Come on, guys. Don't--
- 짜식... - 이거 놔봐
-Now, Harry. -Come and join the big boys.
- 해리 - 보여줄 게 있어
What are you doing?!
뭔데?
-What's this rubbish? -"What's this rubbish? " he says.
- 이 쓰레긴 뭐야? - 쓰레기랜다
-It's the secret to our success. -It's a wrench giving it to you--
- 이건 우리 보물야 - 속 쓰리지만
But we've decided your needs are greater than ours.
너 줄게, 필요할 테니까...
George, if you will.
조지, 읊어
I solemnly swear that I am up to no good.
난 못된 짓을 꾸미고 있음을 엄숙히 선언합니다
" Messrs. Moony, Wormtail, Padfoot and Prongs...
'무니와 웜테일, 패드풋과 프롱스가'
...are proud to present the Marauder's Map."
'제작한 비밀지도'?
We owe them so much.
고마운 분들이지
Hang on. This is Hogwarts. And that--
이건 호그와트잖아!
-No. Is that really--? -Dumbledore.
- 이건...맙소사 - 교장 맞아
-ln his study. -Pacing.
- 서재에서... - 서성대지?
Does that a lot.
늘 그래
-So this map shows--? -Everyone.
- 다 나와? - 누구든!
-Where they are. -What they're doing.
- 매순간 어디서... - 뭘 하는지...
-Every minute. -Every day.
- 매 시간 - 매일 매일
-Brilliant! Where did you get it? -From Filch's office.
- 어디서 났어? - 필치 방에서 슬쩍했지
-First year. -There are seven secret passageways...
- 1학년 때 - 비밀통로는
-...out of the castle. -We'd recommend this one.
- 7갠데... - 이 길이 제일 나아
-The One-Eyed Witch passageway. -Leads you to Honeyduke's.
- 애꾸눈 마녀의 통로지 - 허니듀크 지하실로 통해
Hurry. Filch is heading this way.
서둘러, 필치 온다
And don't forget. When you're done, just give it a tap and say:
볼일 끝나면 지도를 톡 친 뒤
"Mischief managed." Otherwise, anyone can read it.
이렇게 말해 '마법의 장난, 끝'
Now, how much do you want?
얼만큼 달라고?
Delicious.
맛있겠다
It's meant to be the most haunted building in Britain. Did I mention that?
저 집, 귀신 많아 그 얘기 했든가?
Twice.
두 번
Do you want to move a bit closer?
가까이 가볼래?
To the Shrieking Shack?
비명 지르는 오두막에...
Actually, I'm fine here.
그냥 여깄을래
Well, well. Look who's here.
이게 누구야?
You two shopping for your new dream home?
새 집 한 채 사시게?
Bit grand for you, isn't it, Weasle-Bee? Don't your family sleep in one room?
너희 식구는 한 방에 모여 잔다며?
-Shut your mouth, Malfoy. -Not very friendly.
- 닥쳐, 말포이 - 쎄게 나오시네?
Boys, I think it's time we teach Weasle-Bee how to respect his superiors.
윗분 모시는 법 좀 가르쳐야겠다
-Hope you don't mean yourself. -How dare you talk to me!
- 윗분? 웃겨! - 더러운 잡종이
You filthy little mudblood!
누구한테 까불어?
Who is that?
누구야?
-Don't stand there! Do something! -What?
- 어떻게 좀 해봐! - 뭘 해?
What's up, Malfoy? Lost your skis?
스키 잃어버렸냐?
Get out of the way!
저리 비켜!
Move!
비켜!
Malfoy! Wait! Wait!
말포이, 기다려!
Harry!
해리!
Bloody hell, Harry. That was not funny.
왜 장난쳐? 웃음이 나오냐?
Those weasels! Never told me about any Marauder's Map.
치사한 형들, 내겐 숨기고!
He won't keep it. He'll turn it over to Professor McGonagall.
맥고나걸 교수께 반납할 거야
-Aren't you? -Sure. Along with his lnvisibility Cloak.
- 그치? - 투명 망토도 반납하지?
Look who it is. Madam Rosmerta.
로즈메르타 부인이다!
-Ron fancies her. -That's not true!
- 론이 뿅갔어 - 아냐!
-Professor McGonagall! -Cornelius!
- 교수님! - 코넬리우스
Allow me, minister.
열어드리죠, 장관님
-Oh, Hagrid.... -Sorry about that.
- 이런, 해그리드 - 죄송해요
Rosmerta, my dear. I hope business is good.
로즈메르타 장사는 잘 돼요?
It'd be a lot better if the Ministry wasn't sending dementors...
문 닫기 직전이에요 디멘터들이 찾아와
-...into my pub every other night! -We have....
- 수색하는 통에! - 살인범을
-We have a killer on the loose. -Sirius Black in Hogsmeade!
- 잡아야죠 - 시리우스라도 왔나요?
And what would bring him here?
뭘 노리구요?
-Harry Potter. -Harry Potter?
- 해리 포터 - 해리 포터?
Come.
들어갑시다
Harry!
해리!
-No underage wizards allowed in today! -Shut the damn door!
- 미성년자 출입금지야! - 문 닫아!
-So rude. -Thick heads.
- 재수없어 - 얼간이들
-Thick heads?! -How dare they!
- 얼간이? - 어디다 감히?
-Who are they calling thick heads? -Young whippersnappers!
- 누구더러 얼간이래? - 니네가 얼간이다!
Nobody will come to a pub where they'll get scared out of their wits.
공포 분위기에서 장사가 돼요?
Professor Dumbledore doesn't want dementors around the place.
교장이 뭔가 조치를 취할 거예요
Tell me what this is all about.
대체 무슨 사연이죠?
Years ago, when Harry Potter's parents realized they were marked for death--
'그'의 표적이 된 해리 포터 부모가
Remember? They hid. Few knew where they were.
피신했던 거 알죠?
One who did was Sirius Black. And he told You-Know-Who.
피신장소 밀고한 게 시리우스예요
Not only did Black lead him to the Potters that night...
시리우스의 죄는 또 있소
...he also killed Peter Pettigrew!
친구까지 죽였죠 '피터 페티그루'!
-Peter Pettigrew? -Little lump of a boy.
- 피터 페티그루? - 작달막한 친구였죠
-Always trailing after Black. -I remember.
- 시리우스와 다니던 친구예요 - 기억나요
Never let James and Sirius out of his sight.
제임스랑 셋이 삼총사였죠?
-What happened? -Peter tried to warn the Potters...
- 어떻게 됐는데요? - 포터 부부를
...and might have, had he not run into an old friend, Sirius Black.
피신시키려다가 시리우스에게 살해됐죠
Black was vicious. He didn't kill Pettigrew.
그것도 아주 처참히 살해됐소
He destroyed him!
흔적조차 없이!
A finger. That's all that was left. A finger. Nothing else.
남은 건 손가락 하나뿐이었소
Sirius Black may not have put his hands to the Potters...
포터 부부 죽음도
-...but he's the reason they're dead. -He wants to finish things.
- 시리우스 탓예요 - 이젠 해리를 노려요
-I don't believe it. -That's not the worst of it.
- 맙소사! - 더 놀라운 건...
-What could be worse? -This: Sirius Black was...
- 뭐죠? - 시리우스 블랙이
...and remains to this day...
바로 해리 포터의
...Harry Potter's godfather!
대부라는 거예요!
Ron, look!
론, 저것 봐!
-Sorry. Excuse me, excuse me. -Merry Christmas.
- 잠깐만요 - 메리 크리스마스
Harry, what happened?
왜 그래?
He was their friend...
아빠 친구였는데
...and he betrayed them.
배신을 했대
He was their friend!
친구였는데!
I hope he finds me.
날 찾아오라 그래!
Because when he does, I'm gonna be ready!
맞을 준비 돼 있으니까!
When he does, I'm gonna kill him!
나타나면 죽여버릴 거야!
Harry.
해리?
There you are. You came.
왔구나
Are you sure about this, Harry? This is very advanced magic...
정말 자신 있니? 이건 고등마법이야
...well beyond the Ordinary Wizarding Level.
굉장히 어려워
I'm sure.
해 볼래요
Well, everything's prepared.
준비는 해놨다
The spell I'm going to teach you is called the Patronus Charm.
네가 배울 건 패트로누스 마법이야
Did you ever hear of it?
들어봤니?
No? Well....
못 들어봤어?
A Patronus is a positive force. For the wizard who conjures one...
패트로누스는 선한 힘이지
...it works like a shield, with the dementor feeding on it rather than him.
디멘터의 힘을 막아주는 방패의 역할을 한단다
But in order for it to work, you need to think of a memory.
그 마법을 쓰려면 기억을 불러내야 돼
Not just any memory, a very happy memory, a very powerful memory.
아주 행복하고 강렬한 기억...
Can you do this? Yes. Very well.
할 수 있겠어? 좋아
Close your eyes.
눈을 감아
Concentrate.
집중해
Explore your past.
옛일을 기억해봐
Do you have a memory?
떠오르는 거 있니?
Allow it to fill you up.
그 기억 속으로
Lose yourself within it.
완전히 몰입해
Then speak the incantation, Expecto Patronum.
이제 주문을 외워 익스펙토 패트로눔
-Expecto Patronum. -Very good.
- 익스펙토 패트로눔 - 좋아
Shall we? Wand at the ready.
시작할까? 지팡이 내밀고...
Expecto Patronum!
익스펙토 패트로눔!
Expecto.... Expecto....
익스펙토...
Here we go. Come on. Sit up. Deep breaths.
괜찮아 자, 일어나, 심호흡해
It's all right. I didn't expect you to do it the first time.
처음부터 성공할 순 없어
That would have been remarkable. Here, eat this. You'll feel better.
성공하면 이상하지 먹어, 진정될 거야
-That's one nasty dementor. -Oh, no, no, no.
- 그 디멘터, 무섭네요 - 아냐
That was a boggart, Harry. A boggart.
그건 가짜였어, 보가트라구
The real thing would be worse. Much, much worse.
진짜 디멘터는 훨씬 더 무섭지
As a matter of interest, what were you thinking?
행복한 기억으로
-Which memory did you choose? -The first time I rode a broom.
- 뭘 떠올렸니? - 처음 빗자루 탔을 때요
That's not good enough. Not nearly good enough.
그걸론 안 돼, 부족해
There's another. It's not happy, exactly.
또 있긴 한데 행복한 기억은 아녜요
Well, it is.
아니
It's the happiest I've ever felt...
행복한 기억이긴 한데
-...but it's complicated. -ls it strong?
- 좀 복잡해요 - 강렬한 거야?
Then let's give it a try. You feel ready?
그럼 해보자, 준비됐니?
Just do it.
시작하세요
Expecto Patronum!
익스펙토 패트로눔!
Yes!
옳지!
Well done, Harry. Well done!
잘했다, 해리, 훌륭해!
-I think I've had enough for today. -Yes. Sit down. Here.
- 오늘은 그만하죠 - 그래, 앉거라
Eat this, it helps. It really helps.
먹어, 진정될 거야
And just so you know, Harry...
아버질 닮아
...I think you'd have given your father a run for his money. And that...
실력이 대단하구나
...is saying something.
이건 굉장한 칭찬이야
I was thinking of him.
아빠 엄마를
And Mum.
상상했어요
Seeing their faces.
그분들 얼굴을...
They were talking to me.
제게 말을 거셨죠
Just talking.
말을 했어요
That's the memory I chose.
그 기억을 떠올렸어요
I don't even know if it's real.
상상인진 몰라도
But it's the best I have.
제일 행복한 기억이죠
-Beautiful day. -Gorgeous.
- 멋진 날이야 - 멋진 날?
Unless you've been ripped to pieces!
누군 찢겨 죽었어!
Ripped to pieces? What are you talking about?
죽어? 누가 말이야?
-Ronald has lost his rat. -I haven't lost anything!
- 쥐가 없어졌대 - 없어지긴!
-Your cat killed him! -Rubbish.
- 네 고양이가 죽인 거야! - 웃겨!
Harry, you've seen the way that bloodthirsty beast of hers...
스캐버스는 늘 고양이에게 쫓겼어
...is always lurking about. And Scabbers is gone.
헌데 없어졌어!
Well, maybe you should take better care of your pets!
잘 간수 못한 네 잘못이지!
-Your cat killed him! -Did not.
- 네 고양이가 죽였어! - 아냐!
-Did. -Didn't.
- 맞아!
How did it go, Hagrid? The hearing?
청문회 어떻게 됐어요?
Well, first off, the committee members took turns...
청문회 위원들의 일장연설이 있은 뒤
...talking about why we were there.
내가 나가서 말했지
I got up and did my piece. Said how Buckbeak...
벅빅은 착한
...was a good hippogriff, always cleaned his feathers.
히포그리프라고...
And then Lucius Malfoy got up. Well, you can imagine.
그러자 '루시우스 말포이' 말이
He said Buckbeak was a deadly and dangerous creature...
벅빅은 사나운 놈이라
...who would kill you as soon as look at you.
사람을 죽일 수 있다는 거야
And then?
그리고는요?
And then he asked for the worst, did old Lucius.
잔인한 청원을 하더군
-They're not sacking you! -No, I'm not sacked.
- 아저씰 짜르쟤요? - 아니, 난 안 짤려
Buckbeak's been sentenced to death!
벅빅을 사형시킨대!
Spiders! There's-- There's spiders. Spiders. They want me to tap-dance.
거미다! 거, 거미야 거미가 탭댄스 추래
-I don't wanna tap-dance! -You tell those spiders.
- 난 추기 싫어! - 싫다고 해
Right, yeah. Tell them. I'll tell them....
그래, 말할 거야 내일은 말할 거야
-Peter Pettigrew? -Little lump of a boy.
- '피터 페티그루'? - 시리우스 블랙을
-Always trailing after Sirius Black. -Black was vicious.
- 따라다니던 애죠 - 처참히 살해됐소
He didn 't kill Pettigrew, he destroyed him!
흔적조차 없이...
-Put that light out! -Sorry.
- 눈 부셔, 불 꺼! - 죄송해요
-Watch it there, boy. -We're trying to sleep here!
- 뭐하는 거야? - 잠 좀 자자!
Mischief managed. Nox.
마법의 장난 끝! 녹스!
Potter.
포터
What are you doing wandering the corridors at night?
이 밤중에 혼자 복도에서 뭐하니?
I was sleepwalking.
몽유병예요
How extraordinarily like your father you are, Potter.
넌 아빠를 빼닮았어
He, too, was exceedingly arrogant, strutting about the castle.
네 아빠도 재수없게 제멋대로였지
My dad didn't strut. And nor do l.
우리 아빤 안 그랬어요! 저두요
Now, if you don't mind, I would appreciate it if you could lower your wand.
그 지팡이 좀 치워주실래요?
Turn out your pockets.
주머니 비워봐
Turn out your pockets!
주머니 비워보래두!
What's this?
그게 뭐냐?
-Spare bit of parchment. -Really? Open it.
- 그냥 양피지예요 - 펴봐
Reveal your secrets.
네 비밀을 드러내라
Read it.
읽어봐
" Messrs. Moony, Wormtail, Padfoot, and Prongs...
'무니, 웜테일, 패드풋과 프롱스가'
...offer their compliments to Professor Snape and...."
'스네이프 교수께 안부 전합니다'
Go on.
계속 해
"And request he keep his large nose out of other people's business."
'제발 남의 일에 참견 마십시오'
-You insolent little-- -Professor!
- 이런 건방진... - 스네이프 교수!
Well, well. Lupin.
루핀 교수
Out for a little walk in the moonlight, are we?
달밤에 산책하러 나온 사람이 많군
Harry, are you all right?
해리, 괜찮니?
That remains to be seen.
지우지 마
I have now just confiscated a rather curious artifact.
방금 수상쩍은 걸 압수했네
Take a look, Lupin. Supposed to be your area of expertise.
한번 보게 자네 분야 같애
-Clearly, it's full of dark magic. -I seriously doubt it, Severus.
- 어둠의 마법이 가득해 - 장난감 같은데?
It looks as though it's a parchment designed to insult anyone...
뭔지 읽어보려는 사람을 놀리려는...
...who tries to read it. I suspect it's a Zonko product.
종코 가게 물건일 거야
Nevertheless, I shall investigate any hidden qualities it may possess.
혹시 모르니까 조사는 해보겠네
It is, after all, as you say, my area of expertise.
자네 말대로 내 분야니까...
Harry, would you come with me, please? Professor, good night.
해리, 따라올래? 그럼, 잘 자게
Are you deaf? Put that light out!
귀 먹었냐? 불 끄라니까!
Come in.
들어와!
I haven't the faintest idea how this map came to be in your possession...
이걸 왜 갖고 있니?
...but quite frankly, I am astounded that you didn't hand it in.
왜 반납 안 했어?
Did it never occur to you that this, in the hands of Sirius Black...
시리우스의 손에 이게 들어가면
...is a map to you?
널 찾는 지도가 될 거라는 거 몰랐니?
-No. -No, sir.
- 몰랐어? - 네
Your father never set much store by the rules either.
네 아빠도 규칙은 잘 어겼지만
But he and your mother gave their lives to save yours.
널 구하려고 목숨을 버리셨어
Gambling their sacrifice by wandering the castle unprotected...
살인범 출몰하는 성 안을 얼쩡대다
...with a killer on the loose seems to me a poor way to repay them!
아버지 희생을 헛되게 만들래?
Now, I will not cover up for you again.
다신 두둔 안 해줘
-Do you hear me? -Yes, sir.
- 알겠니? - 네
I want you to return to your dormitory and stay there.
기숙사로 가서 꼼짝말고 있어
And don't take any detours. If you do, I shall know.
딴데로 새지 마 넌 내 손 안에 있어
Professor, just so you know, I don't think that map always works.
그 지도가 늘 맞는 건 아니던데요?
Earlier, it showed someone in the castle. Someone I know to be dead.
아깐 죽은 사람도 나오더라구요
Oh, really? And who might that be?
그래? 누구?
Peter Pettigrew.
피터 페티그루요
That's not possible.
그럴 리 없어
It's just what I saw.
제가 본 건 그랬어요
Good night, professor.
안녕히 주무세요
Broaden your minds. You must look beyond.
마음을 열고 멀리 보세요!
The art of crystal gazing is in the clearing of the lnner Eye.
내면을 비워야 미래를 볼 수 있어요
Only then can you see. Try again.
자, 다시 한번 해봅시다
Now, what do we have here?
뭐가 보이나 볼까?
Do you mind me trying?
제가 읽어볼게요
The Grim, possibly.
죽음의 개 같은데요?
My dear, from the first moment you stepped foot in my class...
널 처음 봤을 때 이미 알아봤어
...I sensed that you did not possess the proper spirit...
넌 점술이라는 고상한 학문엔
...for the noble art of Divination. No, you see, there.
소질이 없다는 걸... 자, 이걸 봐라
You may be young in years, but your heart is as shriveled...
넌 나이는 어려도 영혼은 찌들었어
...as an old maid's, your soul as dry as the pages of the books...
네가 집착하는 책 종잇장처럼
...to which you so desperately cleave.
말라 비틀어졌다구
Have I said something?
내가 뭐 잘못 말했니?
She's gone mental, Hermione has. Not that she wasn't always mental...
애가 이상해졌어 원래 좀 이상했지만
...but now it's in the open for everyone to see.
이젠 누가 봐도 맛이 갔어
Hang on.
잠깐만...
-We better take this back. -I'm not going back.
- 갖다주고 오자 - 난 안 갈래
-Fine. See you later. -See you.
- 알았어, 이따 봐 - 그래
Harry Potter....
해리 포터...
-Professor Trelawney-- -He will return tonight.
- 교수님... - 그가 오늘 밤에 온다
Sorry?
네?
Tonight, he who betrayed his friends, whose heart rots with murder...
살인으로 심장이 썩어가는 배신자가
...shall break free.
풀려날 것이다
Innocent blood shall be spilt...
무고한 피가 흐르고
...and servant and master shall be reunited once more.
주인과 부하가 재결합할 것이다
I'm so sorry, dear boy. Did you say something?
미안해 너, 무슨 말 했니?
No.
아뇨
Nothing.
아무 말두요
I can't believe they're going to kill Buckbeak. It's just too horrible.
벅빅을 죽이다니 끔찍해!
-lt just got worse. -What did I say? Father said...
- 웬수들이다! - 벅빅 머리 나 준댔어
...I can keep the hippogriff's head. I'll donate it to the Gryffindors' room.
그리핀도르 휴게실에 기증할까?
This is going to be rich.
부자가 될 거야
-Look who's here. -Come to see the show?
- 이게 누구야? - 구경 가냐?
You! You foul, loathsome, evil little cockroach!
이 못되먹고 비열한 놈!
Hermione, no!
참아!
He's not worth it.
그럴 가치도 없어
Malfoy, are you okay?
말포이, 괜찮니?
-Let's go. Quick. -Not a word to anyone, understood?
- 가자! - 소문 내면 죽어
-That felt good. -Not good, brilliant.
- 속이 시원하네 - 시원한 정도냐? 끝내준다!
Look at him. Loves the smell of the trees when the wind blows through them.
저 녀석 봐 바람 냄새가 좋은가봐
Why don't we just set him free?
놔주면 안 돼요?
They'd know it was me, and then Dumbledore...
그럼 덤블도어 교수가
...would get into trouble. He's coming down, Dumbledore.
곤란해져, 곧 오신댔어
Says he wants to be with me when they....
내 곁에 있어주겠대
When it happens.
형 집행될 때...
Great man, Dumbledore.
참 좋은 분이지
A great man.
좋은 분이야
-We'll stay with you too. -You'll do no such thing!
- 저희도 있을게요 - 그건 안 돼
Think I want you seeing something like that? No.
너흰 그런 거 보면 안 돼
You just drink your tea and be off. Oh. Before you do, Ron....
차나 마시고 가거라 참, 론 ...
Scabbers! You're alive!
스캐버스! 무사했구나!
-Keep a closer eye on your pet. -I think you owe someone an apology.
- 간수 좀 잘 해라 - 사과 안 할거야?
Right. Next time I see Crookshanks, I'll let him know.
크룩생크 만나면 사과할게
I meant me!
나한테 해!
Blimey. What was that?
깜짝이야! 뭐야?
Hagrid!
해그리드!
Oh, crikey.
이런!
No, minister. Over this way.
이쪽입니다
It's late. It's nearly dark. You shouldn't be here.
늦었다, 곧 해 저물어 어서 돌아가
Someone sees you outside this time of night, you'll be in trouble.
이 시간에 나온 거 들키면 혼나!
Particularly you, Harry. With you in a moment!
해리 넌 특히! 나갑니다!
Quick. Quick!
빨리 가, 빨리!
Hagrid.
해그리드
-lt'll be fine. It'll be okay. -Go on, go on!
- 다 잘 될 거예요, 염려마요 - 어서 가!
-That's ling you see over there-- -On the slope.
- 저건 관엽식물 링일세... - 언덕 위에
-On the slope-- Ah, Hagrid. -Professor Dumbledore.
- 언덕 위에... - 덤블도어 교수님
-Good evening. -Minister. Make your way through.
- 안녕하세요 - 들어와서
-Have a tea, if you like. -No, Hagrid.
- 차 한잔 하시죠? - 괜찮아요, 해그리드
-Gentlemen. -I'd like a cup of tea.
- 여러분 - 차 한잔 주세요
Well, I think we should get down to our business, shall we?
자, 그럼 안건을 처리하세
Very well. It is the decision of the Committee for the Disposal...
'위험한 동물 처리 위원회의 결정대로'
...of Dangerous Creatures that the hippogriff Buckbeak...
'히포그리프 벅빅의 형집행을'
...hereinafter called "the condemned," shall be executed this day at sundown.
'금일 해질 무렵 실시한다'
-Dear, dear.... -Now, now, Hagrid. Now, come on.
- 여러분... - 진정해, 해그리드
-All right. It'll be all right. -The execution shall dispatch--
- 괜찮을 거야 - 형집행은...
What?
왜?
I thought I just saw--
뭔가 본 것 같애
-Never mind. -Let's go!
- 잘못 봤나 봐 - 가자!
Buckbeak didn't mean no harm.
벅빅은 악의가 없었어
Oh, no.
이런
He bit me. Scabbers.
날 물었어! 스캐버스!
Ron. Ron!
론!
-Ron! -Scabbers, come back.
- 론! - 스캐버스, 돌아와!
Wait!
기다려!
-Scabbers, you bit me! -Harry, you do realize what tree this is?
- 스캐버스! - 저 나무, 뭔지 기억나?
That's not good. Ron, run!
맙소사, 론, 도망가!
Harry, Hermione, run!
얘들아, 도망가!
It's the Grim!
죽음의 개야!
-Harry! -Ron! Ron, wait!
- 해리! - 론, 기다려!
Harry!
해리!
-Help! -Ron!
- 해리, 도와줘! - 론!
-Ron. Ron.
- 론, 론
Come on!
가자!
Move!
피해!
Duck!
엎드려!
Harry!
해리!
-Oh, I'm sorry. -Don't worry.
- 미안해 - 괜찮아
-Where do you suppose this goes? -I have a hunch.
- 어디로 가는 길일까? - 뭔가 짚혀
I just hope I'm wrong.
아니면 좋겠다
We're in the Shrieking Shack, aren't we?
비명을 지르는 오두막집 안이지?
Come on.
가자
Ron.
론!
-Ron. You're okay. -The dog. Where is it?
- 무사했구나! - 개는 어딨어?
It's a trap. He's the dog. He's an Animagus.
저 사람이 개였어 애니마구스라구!
If you want to kill Harry, you have to kill us too!
해리를 죽이려면 우리도 죽여!
No. Only one will die tonight.
죽는 건 하나야
Then it'll be you!
네가 죽을거야!
Are you going to kill me, Harry?
날 죽일거냐, 해리?
Expelliarmus!
엑스펠리아르무스!
Well, well, Sirius. Looking rather ragged, aren't we?
시리우스, 몰골이 왜 그래?
Finally, the flesh reflects the madness within.
광기가 슬슬 드러나는군
Well, you'd know all about the madness within, wouldn't you?
광기라면 자네도 만만치 않지
-I found him. -I know.
- 녀석이 여깄어 - 알고 있어
-He's here. -I understand.
- 여기 있어 - 알아
-Let's kill him! -No! I trusted you!
- 죽여야 돼! - 난 믿었어요! 교수님을!
And all this time, you've been his friend.
그런데 저자의 친구였군요!
He's a werewolf! That's why he's been missing classes.
저 사람이 늑대 인간이야! 그래서 수업에도 빠진 거야
How long have you known?
언제 눈치챘니?
-Since Professor Snape set the essay. -Well, Hermione.
- 스네이프 교수 숙제할 때요 - 과연, 헤르미온느이군
You are the brightest witch of your age I've ever met.
넌 어리지만 정말 똑똑해
Enough talk, Remus! Come on, let's kill him!
어서 놈을 죽이쟤두!
-Wait! -I did my waiting!
- 기다려! - 오래 기다렸어!
Twelve years of it!
장장 12년간을
In Azkaban!
아즈카반에서!
Very well. Kill him.
좋아, 처치하세
But wait one more minute. Harry has the right to know why.
해리에게 이유는 말해줘야지
I know why.
이유는 알아요!
You betrayed my parents.
당신은 내 부모를
-You're the reason they're dead! -No, it wasn't him.
- 죽게 한 배신자야! - 배신자는
Somebody did betray your parents...
다른 사람이야
...somebody who, until quite recently, I believed to be dead!
난 여태 그자가 죽은 줄 알았다!
-Who was it, then? -Peter Pettigrew!
- 그게 누군데요? - 피터 페티그루
And he's in this room! Right now!
놈은 지금 이 방에 있어!
Come out, come out, Peter!
어서 나와, 피터!
-Come out, come out and play! -Expelliarmus!
- 나랑 놀자구! - 엑스펠리아르무스!
Vengeance is sweet.
복수는 달콤한 거야
How I hoped I'd be the one to catch you.
내 손으로 널 잡게 됐군
Severus--
세베루스...
I told Dumbledore you were helping a friend into the castle. Here's the proof.
그동안 쭉 자넬 의심해 왔는데 증거를 잡았군
Brilliant, Snape.
대단해!
You've put your keen mind to the task and come to the wrong conclusion.
자넨 늘 그 명석한 두뇌로 헛다리만 짚는군
If you'll excuse us, Remus and I have business...
비켜주게, 우린
-...to attend to. -Give me a reason. I beg you!
- 끝낼 일이 있어 - 이유를 대봐!
-Don't be a fool. -He can't help it. It's habit.
- 바보짓 마 - 바보짓도 습관이야
-Be quiet. -Be quiet yourself!
- 시끄러! - 너나 조용히 해!
You two, quarrelling like an old married couple.
둘이 오래된 부부 같군
Run along and play with your chemistry set!
가서 약병이나 갖고 놀아
I could do it, you know.
널 죽일 수도 있지만
But why deny the dementors? They're so longing to see you.
디멘터에게 맡기지 널 애타게 찾고 있거든
Do I detect a flicker of fear? Oh, yes.
두렵나? 그럴 거야
A Dementor's Kiss. One can only imagine what that must be like.
디멘터의 키스는 끔찍하다지?
It's said to be nearly unbearable to witness, but I'll do my best.
차마 눈 뜨곤 못 본다던데 염려마, 참고 봐줄게
Severus, please.
스네이프, 제발!
After you.
앞장 서!
Expelliarmus!
엑스펠리아르무스!
-Harry! What did you just do? -You attacked a teacher!
- 해리, 무슨 짓야? - 교수님을 왜?
-Tell me about Peter. -He was at school with us.
- 피터 얘길 해봐 - 우린 학창 시절
We thought he was our friend!
친구였지
-No. Pettigrew's dead. You killed him! -No, he didn't.
- 피터는 죽었어요, 당신 손에! - 그렇지 않아
I thought so too, until you mentioned Pettigrew on the map!
네가 지도에서 피터를 봤다며?
-The map was lying, then. -The map never lies!
- 지도가 틀렸겠죠 - 틀리지 않아!
Pettigrew's alive! And he's right there!
놈은 살아있어 바로 저깄어!
-Me?! He's mental! -Not you! Your rat!
- 나? 돌았나봐! - 너 말고 네 생쥐!
-Scabbers has been in my family for-- -Twelve years?
- 얜 내가 키운지... - 12년 됐지?
Curiously long life for a common garden rat!
쥐가 명도 길구나!
-He's missing a toe, isn't he? -So what?
- 발가락이 하나 없지? - 그게 뭐요?
-All they could find of Pettigrew was his-- -Finger!
- 피터가 남긴 건... - 손가락 한 개지!
Dirty coward cut it off so everyone would think he was dead!
놈이 자른 거야 죽은 걸로
-And then he transformed into a rat! -Show me.
- 위장하려고! - 입증해 봐요
-Give it to him, Ron. -What are you trying to do to him?
- 어서 드려 - 어쩌려구요?
Scabbers!
스캐버스!
Leave him alone! Get off him! What are you doing?
해치지 마요! 걜 어쩌려는 거야!
Remus?
루핀?
Sirius.
시리우스?
My old friends!
보고 싶었네!
Harry! Look at you. You look so much like your father.
해리, 많이 컸구나 아빠를 꼭 닮았군
-James. We were the best of friends-- -How dare you speak to Harry!
- 네 아빠와 난... - 감히 해리 앞에서
How dare you talk about James in front of him!
제임스 얘길 해?
-You sold James and Lily to Voldemort! -I didn't mean to!
- 넌 볼드모트에게 그를 팔았어! - 어쩔 수 없었어!
The Dark Lord. You have no idea the weapons he possesses!
어둠의 마왕은 무서운 자야
Ask yourself, Sirius! What would you have done?
자네라면 어찌했겠나?
-What would you have done? -Died, rather than betray my friends!
- 응? - 죽음을 택했겠지
James wouldn't have wanted me killed!
제임스라면 날 안 죽일 걸?
Your dad would have spared me! He would have shown me mercy!
네 아빠는 자비를 베풀었을 거야!
Should have realized if Voldemort didn't kill you, we would. Together!
넌 어차피 죽어야 돼 우리 손에라도!
No!
안 돼요!
-Harry, this man-- -I know what he is.
- 해리, 이 자는... - 저도 알지만
But we'll take him to the castle.
성으로 데려가요
-Bless you, boy. Bless you! -Get off!
- 고맙다 해리, 고맙다! - 비켜!
I said we'd take you to the castle.
성으로 데려가서
After that, the dementors can have you.
디멘터에게 넘길 거야
Sorry about the bite. I reckon that twinges a bit.
물어서 미안하다 좀 아프지?
A bit? A bit? You almost tore my leg off!
'좀'이요? 다리 짤릴 뻔했어요!
I was going for the rat.
쥐 쫓다 그랬어
Normally, I have a very sweet disposition as a dog.
개로 변신하면 평소엔 온순해
More than once, James suggested that I make the change permanent.
제임스는 날더러 쭉 개로 살랬었지
The tail I could live with. But the fleas, they're murder.
헌데, 개벼룩을 참기가 힘들어
Okay.
됐어
-You better go. -No. Don't worry, okay?
- 넌 가봐 - 아냐, 괜찮아
It's fine. I'll stay.
여기 있을게
You go, I'll stay.
내가 있을게
-You okay? -I'm fine. Go.
- 괜찮겠니? - 응, 가봐
-That looks really painful. -So painful.
- 정말 아프겠다 - 무지 아파
They might chop it.
잘라내야 될 거야
I'm sure Madam Pomfrey will fix it in a heartbeat.
폼프리 부인이 고쳐줄 거야
It's too late. It's ruined. It'll have to be chopped off.
늦었어, 감염돼서 잘라내야 돼
It's beautiful, isn't it?
정말 아름답지?
I'll never forget the first time I walked through those doors.
첫 입학한 날을 못 잊을 거야
It'll be nice to do it again as a free man.
그때의 자유가 그립구나
That was a noble thing you did back there.
아까 네 행동 훌륭했다
He doesn't deserve it.
죽어 마땅한 놈인데...
I didn't think my dad would have wanted his best friends...
살인하시는 거
...to become killers.
아빤 원치 않을 걸요
Besides, dead, the truth dies with him.
그리고, 살려놔야 진실을 밝히죠
Alive, you're free.
아저씨의 결백도...
Turn me into a flobberworm. Anything but the dementors!
디멘터만은 안 돼!
Ron! Haven't I been a good pet? You won't let them give me...
론, 너와 난 친구였잖아!
...to the dementors, will you? I was your rat!
날 디멘터에게 넘기지 마!
-Sweet, clever girl! Surely you won't-- -Get away from her!
- 똑똑하고 착한 아가씨, 살려줘 - 저리 비켜!
I don't know if you know, Harry...
네가 태어났을 때
...but when you were born, James and Lily made me your godfather.
네 부모가 날 대부로 정했지
I know.
알아요
I can understand if you choose to stay with your aunt and uncle...
이모네서 사는 것도 좋겠지만
...but if you ever wanted a different home....
혹시 딴 데서 살고 싶으면...
What? Come and live with you?
아저씨랑 살자구요?
It's just a thought. I can understand if you don't want to.
그냥 말해봤어 거절해도 이해해
Harry!
해리!
Remus, my old friend. Have you taken your potion tonight?
이보게 루핀, 오늘 약 먹었나?
You know the man you truly are, Remus! This heart is where you truly live! Here!
자네 참 모습은 마음 속에 있어! 바로 여기에!
This flesh is only flesh!
겉모습은 껍데기야!
Expelliarmus!
엑스펠리아르무스!
Harry!
해리!
Remus! Remus!
루핀!
Run! Run!
도망가!
-Come on. -Wait. Wait.
- 가자 - 잠깐만!
Hermione! Bad idea. Bad idea.
뭐해? 미쳤구나, 미쳤어
Professor?
교수님?
Professor Lupin?
루핀 교수님
Nice doggy. Nice doggy!
착하지...
There you are, Potter!
여깄었구나!
Sirius!
시리우스!
Come back here, Potter!
돌아와!
No. Sirius!
안 돼... 시리우스!
Expecto Patronum!
익스펙토 패트로넘!
Harry?
해리?
I saw my dad.
아빠를 봤어
What?
뭐?
He sent the dementors away.
호수 저편에서
I saw him across the lake.
날 구해주셨어!
Harry, they've captured Sirius.
해리, 시리우스가 잡혔어
Any minute the dementors are gonna perform the Kiss.
곧 디멘터의 입맞춤이 있을 거야
-They're gonna kill him? -No. It's worse.
- 죽일 거란 말야? - 아니
Much worse.
그 정도가 아냐
They're going to suck out his soul.
영혼을 다 빨아낼 거야!
Headmaster, stop them.
교수님, 시리우스는
-They've got the wrong man. -It's true. Sirius is innocent.
- 결백해요! - 누명 쓴 겁니다!
-It's Scabbers who did it. -Scabbers?
- 스캐버스 짓이에요 - 스캐버스?
He's my rat, sir.
제 생쥐요
He's not really a rat. He was a rat. He was my brother Percy's rat.
진짜 쥐는 아니죠 원래 형 꺼였는데
-But then they gave him an owl-- -The point is, we know the truth.
- 부모님이... - 믿어주세요!
-Please believe us. -I do, Miss Granger.
- 다 사실예요 - 난 믿지만
But the word of three 1 3-year-old wizards will convince few others.
13살짜리 말을 믿을 사람 드물어
A child's voice, however honest and true...
마음이 닫힌 사람들에겐
...is meaningless to those who have forgotten how to listen.
정직한 소리도 들리질 않지
Mysterious thing, time.
시간은 신비한 거야
Powerful...
잘못 다루면
...and when meddled with, dangerous.
아주 위험하지
Sirius Black is in the topmost cell of the Dark Tower.
시리우스는 탑 꼭대기에 있다
You know the laws, Miss Granger.
규칙은 알고 있지?
You must not be seen.
눈에 띄면 안 돼
And you would do well, I feel, to return before this last chime.
마지막 타종 전에 꼭 돌아와
If not, the consequences are too ghastly to discuss.
안 그러면 무서운 일이 생겨
If you succeed tonight...
성공하면
...more than one innocent life may be spared.
무고한 생명 몇을 구하게 돼
Three turns should do it, I think.
세 번 돌리면 될게다
Oh, and by the way.
참, 그리고
When in doubt, I find retracing my steps to be a wise place to begin.
헷갈릴 땐, 과거를 되짚어 가는게 최선이더라
Good luck.
행운을 빈다
What the bloody hell was that all about?
대체 다 뭔 소리야?
Sorry, Ron, but seeing as you can't walk....
넌 못 걸으니 빠져야겠다
What just happened?
어떻게 된 거야?
-Where's Ron? -7:30.
- 론은? - 7시 반에
Where were we at 7:30?
7시 반에 우리 어딨었지?
I don't know. Going to Hagrid's?
해그리드네 집 쪽?
Come on. And we can't be seen.
가자! 눈에 띄면 안 돼!
Hermione!
헤르미온느!
Hermione! Hermione, wait.
헤르미온느, 같이 가!
Hermione, will you please tell me what it is we're doing?
- 어딜 가는 건데? - 구경 가냐?
You foul, loathsome, evil little cockroach!
이 못되먹고 비열한 놈!
That's us.
우리잖아
Hermione, no! He's not worth it.
참아, 그럴 가치도 없어
This is not normal.
뭔가 잘못됐어
This is a Time-Turner, Harry.
시간 돌리는 시계야
McGonagall gave it to me first term.
맥고나걸 교수가 줬어
This is how I've been getting to my lessons all year.
덕분에 두 강의씩 들었지
-You mean we've gone back in time? -Yes.
- 우리가 과거로 온 거야? - 그래
Dumbledore obviously wanted us to return to this moment.
교장은 뭔가를 되돌려 놓길 원해
Clearly, something happened he wants us to change.
그래서 우릴 과거로 보낸 거야
Good punch.
주먹 쎈데?
Thanks.
고마워
Malfoy's coming.
말포이 온다!
-Run. -Not a word to anyone, understood?
- 같이 가! - 소문내면 죽어
I'm gonna get that jumped-up mudblood! Mark my words.
잡종 기집애 두고보자!
-That felt good. -Not good, brilliant.
- 속 시원하네 - 시원한 정도냐? 끝내준다!
Come on. We should be at Hagrid's.
가자 이러다 늦겠다
Look. Buckbeak's still alive.
벅빅이 아직 살아있네!
Of course.
당연하지!
Remember what Dumbledore said?
교장 얘기 기억나?
If we succeed, more than one innocent life could be spared.
성공하면 몇 생명을 구한댔어
Let's go.
가자!
Here they come. I'd better hurry.
저기 온다, 서둘러야 돼
Fudge has to see Buckbeak before we steal him.
코넬리우스가 벅빅을 보게 해야 돼
Otherwise, he'll think Hagrid set him free.
해그리드가 의심 안 받게...
Scabbers, you're alive!
스캐버스, 무사했구나!
-Keep a closer eye on your pet. -That's Pettigrew.
- 간수 좀 잘 해라 - 저게 피터야!
-Harry, you can't. -He betrayed my parents.
- 나서면 안 돼! - 저 배신자를
-You don't expect me to sit here. -Yes, and you must!
- 구경만 하라구? - 그래, 참아야 돼!
Harry, you're in Hagrid's hut now.
지금 네가 쳐들어가면
If you go bursting in, you'll think you've gone mad.
저 안의 너랑 마주치게 돼!
Awful things happen to wizards who meddle with time.
그럼 혼란이 생겨
We can't be seen.
우릴 보여선 안 돼
Fudge is coming.
장관 온다
And we aren't leaving?
쟤들 왜 안 피하지?
Why aren't we leaving?
왜 안 나오지?
Are you mad?
미쳤어?
That hurt.
얼마나 아팠다구!
Sorry.
미안
We're coming out the back door. Go!
우리 나온다, 가자!
Is that really what my hair looks like from the back?
내 뒤통수가 저렇게 생겼어?
What?
왜?
I thought I just saw....
뭔가 본 것 같애
-Never mind. -Let's go.
- 잘못 봤나 봐 - 가자
Okay, go, Harry. Go!
가!
Get away. Get off.
저리 가, 가!
Minister, I really think I should sign as well.
코넬리우스, 나도 서명하겠네
Yes, very well. Perhaps it would be....
그래, 그러면 더 좋지
Okay, Buckbeak. Come quickly. Come with us now. Come on.
벅빅 이리와! 우리랑 같이 가자
Keep trying. Come on. Quickly.
더 세게 잡아당겨봐!
Buckbeak. Okay? Quickly. Hurry up. Okay?
착하지? 가자, 옳지!
-Your name only. -It's such a very long name....
- 이름만 쓰면 돼 - 이름이 길어서...
Hurry up now, Buckbeak, okay?
빨리 와, 벅빅
Come on. Come on, Buckbeak.
어서, 어서
Come and get the nice dead ferret.
이거 먹어 맛있는 담비야!
-Come on. It's here. Come on, Beaky. -Here we are, minister. Follow me.
- 착하지, 이리 와봐 - 이리 좀 와보게
-Now, look there. -Where?
- 저길 봐 - 어디?
-Look beyond the rocks. -What am I supposed to see?
- 저 바위 뒤... - 뭘 보라구?
Professor Dippet had that ling planted when he was headmaster.
디펫 교수가 교장 때 심은 걸세
-Oh, yes. Indeed, indeed. -And all the strawberries.
- 그래? - 저 딸기 좀 봐
-Come on, Buckbeak. Come on. -I see no strawberries.
- 벅빅, 어서 - 딸기가 어딨어?
-Over there. -Where?
- 저기! - 어디?
-This way.
- 저쪽 - 이리와
-Let's get this over, please. -All right.
- 빨리 끝내세 - 알았네
But where is it?
어디 갔지?
I saw the beast, just now.
방금 전에 봤는데!
-Not a moment ago! -How extraordinary.
- 분명히 봤어! - 이상하군!
Buckbeak.
벅빅!
Come now, Dumbledore. Someone's obviously released him.
누가 풀어준 게 분명해
-Hagrid? -Buckbeak.
- 해그리드? - 전 아닙니다!
I don't think the minister's suggesting you had anything to do with this.
장관이 자넬 의심할 린 없지
How could you? You've been with us all the time.
자넨 우리랑 함께 있었잖나
-Right. -Well, well....
- 그럼요! - 자, 그럼
We must search the grounds.
숲을 뒤져보세!
Well, search the skies, if you must, minister.
이왕이면 하늘도 뒤져봐
Meanwhile, I'd like a nice cup of tea or a large brandy.
난 차나 브랜디를 한잔 마셔야겠군
Oh, executioner, your services are no longer required.
집행관, 이제 그만 가봐요
Thank you.
수고했소
You'll find no small glasses in this house, professor.
저희 집엔 작은 잔이 없는데요
-Come on. -This way.
- 이리 와! 어서! - 이리 와
This way, now.
이리 와, 착하지!
-Now what? -We save Sirius.
- 이젠? - 시리우스를 구해야지
-How? -No idea.
- 어떻게? - 나도 몰라!
-Look. It's Lupin. -Immobulus!
- 루핀이야! - 이모불루스!
And Snape's coming.
스네이프가 온다
And now we wait.
이대로 기다려?
-At least someone's enjoying himself. -Yeah.
- 한 녀석은 살판 났네 - 그래
-Hermione? -Yeah?
- 헤르미온느? - 왜?
Before, down by the lake, when I was with Sirius...
시리우스와 호숫가에 있을 때
...I did see someone.
누군가를 봤어
That someone made the dementors go away.
그가 디멘터를 쫓아줬지
With a Patronus.
패트로누스로?
I heard Snape telling Dumbledore.
스네이프 말로는
According to him...
최강의 마법사만
...only a really powerful wizard could have conjured it.
그 마법 쓸 수 있대
It was my dad.
우리 아빠였어
My dad conjured the Patronus.
아빠가 해냈어
-Harry, but your dad's-- -Dead. I know.
- 네 아빤... - 돌아가신 거 알아
I'm just telling you what I saw.
본 대로 말한 거야
Here we come.
우리가 온다
You see Sirius talking to me there?
둘이 얘기하지?
-He's asking me to come live with him. -That's great.
- 날더러 함께 살쟀어 - 잘됐네
When we free him, I'll never have to go back to the Dursleys'.
이제 시리우스를 구해주면
It'll just be me and him.
함께 살 수 있어
We could live in the country...
하늘 보이는
...someplace you can see the sky.
시골집이 좋겠지?
He'll like that after all those years in Azkaban.
감옥에 오래 있었으니까...
Harry!
해리!
Run!
도망가!
Let's go.
가자!
-What are you doing? -Saving your life.
- 왜 그래? - 널 구하려고!
Thanks.
고맙다
-Great. Now he's coming for us. -Yeah, I didn't think about that. Run!
- 우리한테 온다! - 그건 생각 못했네, 뛰어!
That was so scary.
너무 무서웠어
Poor Professor Lupin's having a really tough night.
불쌍한 교수님, 힘드시겠다
Sirius. Come on!
시리우스! 가자!
-This is horrible. -Don't worry.
- 너무 끔찍해 - 걱정 마
My dad will come. He'll conjure the Patronus.
우리 아빠가 구해주실 거야
Any minute now.
금방 오실 거야!
Right there. You'll see.
바로 저기였어!
Harry, listen to me. No one's coming.
해리, 아무도 안 와
Don't worry, he will. He will come.
걱정 마, 오셔, 꼭 오셔!
-Sirius. -You're dying...
- 시리우스 - 죽어가고 있어
...both of you.
둘 다...
Harry!
해리!
Expecto Patronum!
익스펙토 패트로넘!
You were right, Hermione.
네 말대로 그건
It wasn't my dad I saw earlier. It was me!
아빠가 아니었어, 나였어!
I saw myself conjuring the Patronus before.
패트로누스 마법을 해봤거든!
I knew I could do it this time because...
과거에 한 걸 봤잖아
...well, I had already done it.
그래서 해낸 거야
-Does that make sense? -No.
- 그게 말이 되나? - 안 돼!
But I don't like flying...!
근데 나 무서워!
Bombarda!
봄바르다!
I'll be forever grateful for this...
너희들 신세
...to both of you.
절대 안 잊으마
-I want to go with you. -One day, perhaps.
- 저도 갈래요 - 아직은 안 돼
For some time, my life will be too unpredictable.
내 삶이 너무 불안정해
And besides...
게다가
-...you're meant to be here. -But you're innocent.
- 넌 아직 여기 있어야 돼 - 결백하시잖아요
And you know it.
네가 알면 됐어
And for now, that will do.
그걸로 충분해
I expect you're tired of hearing this...
지겹게 들었겠지만...
...but you look so like your father.
넌 아빠를 꼭 닮았어
Except your eyes.
눈만 빼고...
-You have-- -My mother's eyes.
눈은 -... - 엄마 눈이죠?
It's cruel that I spent so much time with James and Lily, and you so little.
네 부모님과 지낸 시간은 내가 더 많지만
But know this:
이걸 잊지 마
The ones that love us never really leave us.
사랑하는 사람에겐 이별이 없어
And you can always find them...
늘 곁에 살아있지
...in here.
이 속에...
You really are the brightest witch of your age.
넌 정말 영리한 마법사야
We have to go.
가야 돼!
-Well? -He's free. We did it.
- 해리? - 성공했어요
Did what?
뭘?
Good night.
잘 자라
How did you get there?
니들 왜 거깄어?
I was talking to you there. And now you're there.
방금 여기서 나랑 얘기했잖아
-What's he talking about, Harry? -I don't know.
- 쟤, 뭔 소리니? - 몰라
Honestly, Ron. How can somebody be in two places at once?
어떻게 동시에 두 곳에 있어?
Hello, Harry.
안녕, 해리
I saw you coming.
오는 거 봤다
I've looked worse, believe me.
그때 내 꼴, 가관이었지?
-You've been sacked. -No.
- 해고되셨어요? - 아니
No. I resigned, actually.
스스로 사임한 거야
Resigned? Why?
사임이요? 왜요?
Well, it seems that somebody let slip the nature of my condition.
내 정체에 관해 누가 소문을 냈어
This time tomorrow, the owls will start arriving and parents will not want...
곧 학부모들의 편지가 빗발칠 거야
...well, someone like me teaching their children.
나 같은 선생, 누가 원하겠니?
-But Dumbledore-- -He has already...
- 교장께선... - 교장도
...risked enough on my behalf.
날 위해 하실 만큼 했어
Besides, people like me are....
그리고 나 같은 사람은...
Well, let's just say that I'm used to it by now.
이런 일에 익숙해져 있단다
Why do you look so miserable, Harry?
표정이 왜 그래?
None of it made any difference.
달라진 게 없어요
-Pettigrew escaped. -Didn't make any difference?
- '피터'도 도망갔고... - 달라진 게 없긴!
It made all the difference in the world. You uncovered the truth.
많은 게 달라졌지! 넌 진실을 밝혀서
You saved an innocent man from a terrible fate.
시리우스를 구했어
It made a great deal of difference.
그건 커다란 변화야
If I am proud of anything...
난 네가 자랑스럽다
...it is of how much you have learned this year.
넌 좋은 제자였어
Now, since I am no longer your teacher...
이젠 선생이 아니니
...I feel no guilt whatsoever about giving this back to you.
죄책감 없이 돌려줘도 되겠군
So now I'll say goodbye, Harry.
그만 작별하자, 해리
I feel sure we'll meet again sometime.
언젠간 또 만나겠지
Until then...
잘 있거라
...mischief managed.
마법의 장난 끝!
Stand back, I said! Or I'll take it upstairs if you don't settle.
자꾸 만지면 2층으로 가져간다!
Harry.
해리!
Wherever did you get it?
어디서 샀니?
Can I have a go, Harry? After you, of course.
나중에 나도 태워줘
-What are you talking about? -Quiet.
- 뭘 말야? - 조용히 해!
Let the man through. I didn't mean to open it, Harry.
수선 떨긴... 포장이 풀렸다고
It was badly wrapped. They made me do it.
형들이 열어보랬어
Did not.
우리가 언제?
-It's a Firebolt. -It's the fastest broom in the world.
- 파이어볼트야 - 엄청 빠른 최신형이야!
For me?
내게 보낸 거야?
-But who sent it? -No one knows.
- 누가? - 모르지
This came with it.
이것도 왔어
-Go on, Harry! -Yeah, let's see.
- 빨리 타봐! - 그래
How fast is it, Harry?
- 얼마나 빠르니? - 퀴디치 우승은 맡아놨다
Lumos.
루모스
I solemnly swear that I am up to no good.
난 못된 짓을 꾸미고 있음을 엄숙히 선언합니다
Mischief managed.
마법의 장난 끝!
Nox.
녹스!